[Music]
focus
ideate innovate enable
icici lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards
[Music]
a very good evening ladies and gentlemen
i'm ridhoo bhandari from network 18 and
i'd like to extend a very warm welcome
to all of you
at the sixth edition of icici lombard
general insurance and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards well it's a
constantly evolving
and globally shrinking as well as
digitally connected world
where new business threats are erupting
every single day
and risk management has become one of
the most rapidly changing business
functions
in these times while not taking risk in
business
is perhaps the biggest risk of all not
being prepared for risk
is equally risky business so as global
businesses uh
get caught in the crosshairs of
geopolitics cyber security threats
and extreme climate change the function
of risk management
has become more challenging than ever
before
even as technology unlocks new
opportunities the top concerns for
global businesses
across sectors and scale today are cyber
security as well as data theft because
even one remote attack
can severely impact not just the
reputation but also
the bottom line of a company the ongoing
outbreak of the coronavirus is another
case in point
of a threat that businesses were really
not prepared for
a threat that has really disrupted the
supply chains of
several sectors especially in southeast
asia as
china grapples with this emergency and
really its exports get locked down
so these new age risks are many and the
thing about them is that
they're all unique in a sense that they
cannot be traced back into history
hence the risk managers of tomorrow have
to constantly evolve
and they have to have the foresight and
of course have to act fast
and that's the genesis of this platform
the india risk management awards a one
of its kind initiative
by icici lombard general insurance and
cnbc tv 18
to recognize those organizations that
have created
and adopted world-class risk management
practices
over the last five years this has become
the most coveted platform for
recognizing
india's best risk management teams and
tonight
we're here to felicitate the winners of
season six
and now to set the ball rolling i'd like
to invite on stage cnbc tv 18's
executive editor
lata venkatesh to please come and
deliver the welcome address
really the biggest risk is man
himself or woman herself isn't it
the biggest financial problems or the
biggest problems that have created
joblessness so poverty or sudden uh
decreases in purchasing power
are all man-made maybe you will argue
that the natural disasters are also
man-made to some extent
but the risk management that we are
obviously studying
and trying to master many of them are
man-made
problems and that's why we extended this
invitation to give away the awards and
to speak to us about risk
to professor carmen reinhardt the last
and the most famous
of their books carmen reinart and
kenneth rogoff
eight centuries of financial folly each
time in the eighth centuries
people have said this time is different
and bingo it's another asset bubble
someone who has studied eight centuries
of financial folly
is here to tell us how you can manage
these man-made risks
of getting carried away by acid bubbles
or not
noticing a financial risk so we are
looking forward to the speech
from carmen reinhardt and hopefully
that's going to make us all a little
more alert
a little more careful uh and much
more mature in dealing with both
prosperity
and with down slides uh my hearty
congratulations to all the winners
it was a great learning experience
sitting with the jury and
trying to think trying to learn from
these erudite and expert people
how they assess risk and how they assess
other risk managers
we will be able to learn a lot more from
them through the course of today
but thank you very much everybody and
many congratulations
hope you all have a great evening
thank you very much lata for setting the
tone of the evening
and now i'd like to invite on stage the
man who has staunchly supported this
initiative and these awards for all of
their six editions
pagavdas gupta managing director and ceo
at icici lombard general
[Music]
uh a warm welcome to each one of you to
the sixth edition of the india risk
management award
this platform uh that we are here today
irma
is uh synonymous with our risk
management journey at isil lombard
it was around 2012-13 when
we took a you know huge leap of faith
into this space
it was definitely uncertain we were not
sure that this was the direction that
would work because prior to this
our focus was limited to risk transfer
what
traditional role the you know the
traditional role that insurers play
but somehow we strongly believe that we
could play a bigger role
in managing the risk of clients
from being a risk financier or risk
transfer partner we wanted to
be a risk management partner for india
inc
i'm happy to share with you today that
we believe that we've made tremendous
progress in that journey
today when we meet clients our
discussion is not
about products about fire or about rates
our discussion is about working
hand-in-hand with clients
risk management challenges about
real-time risk monitoring using some of
the on-site technology tools
that we've developed and most
importantly
about providing customized solutions
specific to the client's needs
and i think to us this approach is
working as we speak
about 3000 corporates large small
enterprises embrace our solution
solution
now every journey of transformation
because for the for us this was a
transformative journey
is anchored on multiple pillars
this is where india risk management
award comes in
it's been six years since the time that
we launched this platform dedicated to
risk management
in association with cnbc tv18 who've
been a wonderful partner for us
over the years it's become the benchmark
for the industry
to promote the cause of risk management
among india inc
now i say look ahead while we've made
some progress i believe we have a long
way to go
risk management as lata said is becoming
even more critical day by day
and if you want to build an organization
which is stable sustainable over a long
period of time risk management becomes
important
as we all know we are constantly being
bombarded by risks
both traditional and new age at one end
uh
you know as you remember last year we
saw floods across 13 states of india
which is
never happened in the past last year was
the weakest you know wettest year for
us in india the losses that india
suffered economic losses was
roughly about 40 000 crores
unfortunately only eight percent of
those were insured
on the other hand instance of cyber
attacks data breaches
ransomware malware are becoming more and
more prevalent
india alone witnessed more than 1800
devices being impacted
per minute last year due to such attacks
it's a remarkable number the 1800
devices being impacted per impacted per
minute
so what is more critical in this you
know is is also the suddenness and your
uniqueness
of these attacks it's very very
difficult to prepare for them and in
fact when
we do these surveys that we do with our
clients this year when we did the survey
with top 100 corporates
this risk is emerged as one of the top
three risks and
clients are conveying their anxiety
towards this new age risk
now if we together have to counter this
dual onslaught of old and new risks
we believe that the only way forward is
for insurers to forge a partnership with
corporate india we need to work
hand in hand in tandem to share data
insights perspectives experiences to
overcome this manners
we must get proactive in setting
processes to prevent risk in
incidents and work together to
continuously promote
a risk culture what's also important
is to share learnings from each other
and from experts
in the domain of risk management thank
you for joining us
and wish you a great evening ahead
[Applause]
icici lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards
well uh like mr dos gupta and lata
before him just said that we are all
extremely eager to hear from our chief
guest tonight
carmen reinhardt she's of course a
renowned
american economist and she's on the
advisory panel
of the federal reserve bank of new york
she has been listed on the foreign
policies top
hundred global thinkers and thompson
reuters the world's
most influential scientific minds
amongst many other lists
indeed we are extremely excited and
honored to have you here with us
carmen yes keep the applause going
ladies and gentlemen
for our chief guest tonight carmen
reinhardt professor of economics
at the harvard kennedy school
what i'd like to leave you with tonight
is
a brief tour of
global risk risk management is
so fundamental if one looks back through
history
the amount of welfare that could have
been
increased just by avoiding
bad really bad outcomes forget about
doing great things if
you could just avoid crises could avoid
bad outcomes
extreme bad outcomes this is based on
analysis that i've done is significantly
greater
as we've heard there of course are new
risks
risks associated with
technology risks associated
with things ranging from identity theft
to hacking to of course
the ongoing concerns
maybe some of these are fast moving and
some are slow moving
off climate change those are the newer
wave of risk
however the problem for all of you and
for all of us
is that while there's new risks coming
on board the old ones do not really go
away
the focus of my work is on
the old ones today i find myself having
to start out with
what are some of the global risks
associated with a coronavirus
not from a medical standpoint let's be
very clear but from the economic
impacts let me start out by saying this
is very pertinent
to the discussion of the impacts of the
coronavirus
when people talk about or the
financial press or the president general
makes references
to the sars epidemic in 2003
china's footprint or china's weight
in global gdp was less than a quarter
of what it is today so
even if one were to take the exact
same shock the global repercussions of
today
are an order of magnitude uh greater let
me say that the big
big handicap that i face here
or that most analysts would face
in talking about the impacts of any
uh epidemic is that we do not
observe the counter factuals the most
dramatic of these this was also the you
know the spanish flu
of of this is also world war one so it's
really hard to separate
things but this had a devastating
impact on the global economy and of
course on
the the uh toll it took on in in lives
was on a different scale from anything
we've seen
since uh world war one
the effects that you see here for sars
or for the hong kong clue
even for the asian flu seem to be very
modest
but the fact that i'd like to highlight
is we do not
observe the counterfactual these past
pandemics have tended to go
in cycles the most affected countries
by what's going on in china fall into
two groups
these are the commodity exporters
uh and this really captures
most of western hemisphere central and
south america it captures a bunch of
sub-saharan africa
and parts of of asia because
their terms of trade are directly
impacted and
it affects those countries that have the
obvious large-scale trade
and services and these countries by the
way had been
hurting earlier prior to the corona
virus because of the trade
slump the takeaway again a silver lining
is that in the context of the indian
economy
which does not fall into the commodity
exporting category
quite the country it's a prime it's a
big importer of oil
so the decline oil prices has actually
positive consequences for both growth
and and inflation
uh and it does not fall into one of the
big uh trading partners in merchandise
and tourism like thailand or singapore
or korea
the global downturn was exacerbated by a
sharp contraction in global trade
which was largely the result of
protectionist policies
if you move to the current period
the measure of the global
change in trade and it's been in
negative territory
on a sustained basis and this is really
the first time since the global
financial crisis
first of all the the global slowdown in
trade preceded
the the china-u.s dispute it started
with a global financial crisis
it picked up momentum when
spain and ireland and portugal and
greece
when periphery europe could not finance
its current account deficits
so they had to contract trade that's the
first wave the second wave came with
brexit
the third wave came with trump and
i don't think that third wave is really
over
the democrats and trump cannot agree
on taxes cannot agree
on regulatory reforms cannot agree
on most things but one thing where they
do agree
is their skepticism
about trade and their skepticism about
china i think the country's
most affected have been those obviously
that have been skewed more towards
manufacturing
but i think the bigger
slowdown has been in those economies
like china
like germany like singapore uh
like korea that are more uh geared
towards
uh manufacturing now the next
uh point that i'd like to make
relates to the unintended consequences
of these super low
interest rates we all know that
low interest rates make indebtedness
uh getting indebted easier it is
and that's exactly what has happened
we've seen
uh a surge in
uh corporate indebtedness a lot
of the indebtedness is coming
in riskier uh corporations
i haven't said anything about
india but in each case we all
have our own homegrown uh
sources of risk one of the uh
headlines that one sees when one reads
about india is look growth has been
slowing
more or less steadily for a few years
now
and we're certainly off those heady
double-digit days
uh before the global financial crisis if
you
backtrack to the three years before the
global financial crisis we had
real credit that is credit divided by
cpi real credit growth
of over 20 percent uh usually during
periods where you have credit booms
they're follow usually by credit bus and
part of that has an element of over
lending
uh and lower quality lending during uh
boom periods and part of that takes time
to unwind i think the risk
that i'd like to flag before i turn to
the more generic
risks of emerging markets in the context
of india
is that it's been very slow
in cleaning up the balance sheet
it's easier said than done quite
obviously
it means taking on and recognizing
losses
but learn in the negative sense of what
not to do
in mimicking japan or
europe in a much slower tackling of
bad loans india has the great
benefit that its debt is in domestic
currency
and held domestically which is
a big plus but let me also say
india has always been on the high end
of the emerging market spectrum india
and brazil
are among the more indebted uh
emerging markets this is not
a source of immediate concern but it is
a source of vulnerability
if you think that that numbers that i
showed you for emerging markets
look not so good they're actually
worse i on that uplifting note i'll
conclude well it's time now for the
awards ceremony and the winner is
icici lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards
[Music]
very good evening ladies and gentlemen
i'm ridhoo bhandari from network 18 and
i'd like to extend a very warm welcome
to all of you
at the sixth edition of icici lombard
general insurance and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards a one of
its kind initiative
by icici lombard general insurance and
cnbc tv18
to recognize those organizations that
have created
and adopted world-class risk management
practices
over the last five years this has become
the most coveted platform for
recognizing
india's best risk management teams and
tonight
we are here to felicitate the winners of
season six
and for these first set of awards i'd
also like to invite
vs parkhurst group cfo and group cio
at mahindra in mahindra to please join
the presenters
the first set of awards this year is for
best risk management
framework and systems they recognize the
initiatives taken by a company
to build a comprehensive risk management
framework
to mitigate macro level company-wide
risks
our first award category this evening is
best
risk management framework and systems
emerging
indian companies and the winner is
the winner is cpp group
[Music]
[Applause]
and now let's find out who the second
winner of the category is
the winner is dr lal patlabs
[Music]
all right moving on to our next award
category this evening
best risk management framework and
systems
it ites let's take a look at the winner
the winner is gem pact limited
our next award category tonight is for
best risk management framework and
systems
in sustainability and the winner is
the winner is sri cement limited
[Applause]
moving on to the next category at the
india risk management awards 2020
this one is best risk management
framework and systems
fmcg and the winner is
the winner is tata global beverages
[Music]
[Applause]
limited
[Music]
[Applause]
and for the next set of awards i'd like
to invite on stage
ramesh swaminathan head of corporate
center larson and two bro
to please join us here on stage
well our fifth award category this
evening is best risk management
framework and systems
telecom and the award goes to
[Music]
the winner is reliance geo infocomm
limited
[Applause]
and now for our next category best risk
management framework
and systems auto ancillary
and the award goes to the winner is
[Music]
seat limited
moving on to our next award category
this evening best risk management
framework and systems
metals and mining and this award goes to
the winner is tata steel limited
all right up next is the category best
risk management framework and systems
power
and the award in this one goes to
the winner is the tata power company
[Applause]
[Music]
limited
thank you uh gentlemen i'm going to
request the two of you to please take
your seats and request the ladies to
stay back
for a fireside chat and lata is going to
be interacting with our chief guest
carmen reinhardt
so we are taking a short break from the
awards we will resume
these after this very quick conversation
icici lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards
[Music]
my first question i didn't mean to build
it because you also raised that issue
are we a bit of children of the 2008
crisis
that we call everything a crisis i mean
maybe more scared of financial events
than we have been in the past is there
is there that likelihood
i i really don't think that uh
we always can talk about
in the what would call systemic
which is what we saw in 2008 2009
and then there's always milder um
let me say that uh
in terms of how would i characterize
some of the problems i described for
india
in in in banking uh
some of those had the element of boom
boss this was around
you know the the 2008 2008.
uh and some of them are what i would
call slower burn they're more
structural and
this has to do with uh the uh
credit allocation in the
publicly owned banks so they don't have
that
crisis crisis that things are gonna
you know and to some important degree
the same distinction is applicable when
we talk about climate change
uh climate change is i mean it can it
can be very
drastic it's the uh
the real threat
in in the real threat in uh
economies that are facing like australia
uh large-scale fire or a tropical storm
that's that
that's something but many of those risks
are slow or burn
but there's still risks um and that's
what i tried to highlight in some of my
presentations
the other uh issue that comes to the
mind is
that in spite of this exponential
increase
in government debt and the fact that
corporate samoan did it than
ever before or certainly more than they
were in the 2008 contraction
and thirdly as you pointed out that
interest rates are already
negative and so even the monetary space
is next to nothing
in spite of all this we see uh global
markets
uh equity markets reaching out to
old-time highs
and this is especially the case the
united states which also has much less
monetary space and practically even less
fiscal space are we uh is this
indicating something different that
something right is happening
or is it indicating that this is a blind
spot and we better be worried about the
way equity markets are charging
there are things that are different
there always are we
in our work can rogue off an eye that
this time is different it's meant to be
ironic but that's really about human
nature which seldom is different but let
me get to your question on equity
markets um
part of the equity market story is
definitely tied to the exceptionally
low for long uh interest rates
there is a search for yield uh
the search for yield is not just
it is asset managers that managing
pension funds
asset managers that were once
predominantly
in fixed income and have had to seek
higher returns in the equity market
it is sovereign wealth funds that
historically
like central banks were predominantly
a fixed income and have to so
there are structural elements to the
uh shift to the extent that
some of the reasons some of the reasons
that
uh interest rates are low have to do
with uh our aging population
um some of them have to do with lower
productivity so some of these
trends to lower interest rates are
secular
how however one has to be prepared
that to the extent that
some of the interest rate decline is not
permanent
that there could be uh adverse shocks
inflation surprises and the like
that would lead even without melodrama
to some increase in interest rates
um then i think uh
those equity markets will be sorely
uh tested because right now i think
there's a great deal of complacency
that it's not that rates are low for
long is that
inflation is dead and rates are low
forever which is
saying forever in economics it's always
dangerous
uh that's sort of a rule of thumb okay
may i
uh invite mr bhargavas gupta to join us
[Applause]
is a veteran of managing risk so i
thought i should heard a few questions
at you as well
you know we've been discussing a lot of
financial issues and
how those risks can be managed and
mitigated but
uh you know what you must now be
encountering
are uh you know existential risks for
instance television
seriously disrupted by digital so many
people not watching our programs except
perhaps
what's you know live stock markets the
rest of it is available digitally
only sports is watched because it's a
live event so
similar disruptions we have seen for the
automobile sector with
millennials not wanting to own a car how
do you manage these kinds of risks
so little i don't think that's something
that we insurers manage that
marriage it's uh i think each company
has to
think about how do they manage their
existence and uh
you know you know ultimately we are all
serving customers
customers are human beings who have
needs which transcend time
right of course these change and morph
in some way or form but
the foundation of those needs are
probably similar what you're talking
about
is let's say in the case of a car is a
transportation need you want to move
from one place to another
in the case of television it's maybe
information or
entertainment the way you provide that
uh solution to your customer can change
and that's what maybe technology does
i think the other aspect of technology
is that you know it creates disruption
but it also creates opportunity
uh you know for example when we look at
risk for our own businesses
we talk about catastrophic risks and we
talk about event risk etc
and let's say in the past traditionally
we would have
been waiting for it to happen and then
we come in and you know let's say
you know pay a claim today you can
actually monitor
and hence prevent some of these events
using sensors and
and you know for example in the
automobile example that you're talking
about one of the biggest worries that we
have as insurers is that
if everyone moves into autonomous
vehicles sell driven cars
the rate of accidents dropped by eighty
percent what happens to our business
you're also disruption right exactly if
i if i can take
you know the last question from you you
know you have talked about the fact that
the last question that in your slide was
will u.s dollar remain the reserve
correct currency we were
you know we were talking there that this
is probably one of the most interesting
question to ask
so let me ask you that question since
you didn't answer in your presence so
happy
i'm so happy you you've done that um
look i just finished a study with ken
ken rogoff who was here
uh last year and ethan elseski a former
student of mine
uh looking at this very issue
if anything the dollar has gained ground
in the last two years because the euro
uh has lost ground and the euro has lost
ground because
yes there is one euro one currency but
there isn't a unified debt market you
have a very fragmented you have boons
you have greek debt
it's not a it's a fragmented uh market
um so what worries me is what the
so-called old tripping dilemma in which
to serve us
as reserve currency
you issue more debt because the world
wants to hold more debt
but at the same time you saw the debt
numbers
for the us so at what at one point in
time
is to the two clash you know does the
does the us yes uh the
rest of the world wants more debt will
issue more debt and at what at one point
does that lead to a dollar depreciation
at the moment
there's no alternative to the dollar
that's the no
big alternatives uh but that may change
over time
well it's an interesting conversation
thank you very much
carmen reinhardt it was a pleasure
speaking with you
as well thank you very much for joining
us in this chat icici lombard
and cnbc tv 18 present india risk
management awards
[Music]
well it's uh time now to resume our
awards ceremony
and for these for the next set of awards
i'd also like to invite on stage rui
bastos
cio of reliance industries to join the
presenters
all right then let's move on to our next
award category this evening
best risk management framework and
systems business continuity
and this award goes to
the winner is tata consultancy services
limited
[Music]
moving on to our next category at the
india risk management awards 2020
best risk management framework and
systems cyber security
and the winner is
the winner is wns global services
private limited
[Applause]
[Music]
well up next is the award category best
risk management framework and systems
risk governance and the jury had a tough
task
selecting the winner for this one so
after much deliberation
they decided to give it to two companies
yes we have two winners this year in
this category so let's
in an alphabetical order take a look at
the first winner
the winner is ashok leyland limited
[Music]
[Applause]
so let's take a look at the second one
now
the winner is the tata power company
[Music]
limited
[Applause]
[Music]
for the next set of awards uh i'd like
to welcome
on stage whippin cirelia cro visa south
asia
to please come here and join the
presenter
[Applause]
and our next award category for the
evening
is best risk management framework and
systems
technology and let's find out who the
winner is
the winner is larson and two bro limited
[Applause]
[Music]
moving on the next one is best risk
management framework in systems
psu and
the winner is
the winner is ongc videsh limited
and it's time for the final two awards
of the night and for these i'm going to
invite
our jury members back on stage uh rame
swaminathan
and rui bastos please join us up here
well our next award category is best
risk management framework and systems
private company and the winner is
the winner is ashok leyland limited
[Applause]
[Music]
and it's time to announce the final
award of the evening
and the category is best risk management
framework and systems
conglomerate the winner is
larson and two bro limited
[Music]
and i'm going to invite all the winners
of tonight to please come up here for a
group photo opportunity
the defining memory of this year's india
risk management awards
icici lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards
focus ideate innovate
enable